George Lardner Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Part I: Subject File, 1923-1997 (Box 1-285)
  - Rehnquist, William H.
    - Research material
      - Chief Justice nomination
        - Correspondence, 1986
        - Questions, 1986
        - Statements and testimony, 1986, (2 folders) (Box 202)
        - Witness lists, 1986
      - Financial papers, 1985-1986
      - Interviews of clerks, 1977, undated
      - Legal documents
        - Laird v. Tatum, 1972-1975, 1986, undated
        - Miscellaneous, 1952-1953, 1972, 1977, 1985-1986
      - Library of Congress documents, 1940, 1949-1957, undated, (3 folders)
      - Miscellany, 1954, 1972-1986, undated
      - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1950-1958, 1969-1987, undated, (5 folders) (Box 203)
      - Office of Legal Counsel, Department of Justice
        - 1969
        - 1970, (2 folders)
        - 1971, (3 folders) (Box 204)
      - Shorewood Ripples, 1940-1942, 1984-1985
      - Speeches and writings, 1957-1959, 1973-1986
      - United States Supreme Court nomination
        - U.S. Senate
          - Floor debates, 1971, (2 folders)
          - Report, 1971
        - U.S. Senate Committee on the Judiciary, hearings, 1971, (2 folders) (Box 205)
  - Richmond, Frederick, 1982
  - Rostenkowski, Daniel, congressional election campaign committee, 1984
  - Ruby Ridge, Idaho, law enforcement siege of Weaver family residence
    - Articles, 1995, undated, (3 folders)
    - Correspondence, 1995, undated
    - Interviews, 1995
    - Notes, 1995-1996, undated
    - Photographs, undated
    - Research material (Box 206)
      - Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, and Firearms (BATF)
        - Reports and miscellany, 1989-1995, undated
        - Transcripts, taped conversations of Randy Weaver, 1987-1989, undated, (3 folders)
      - Federal Bureau of Investigation
        - Freeh, Louis, speeches, 1995
        - Interviews and statements, 1992-1995
        - Logs, 1992-1995
        - Miscellany, 1991-1995, undated
        - Press releases, 1993-1995, undated
        - Reports, 1989-1995, undated
      - General
        - Craig, Larry, 1985-1996, undated
        - Degan, Karen and William, 1992-1995, undated
        - Law enforcement reforms, 1993-1995, undated
        - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1984-1996, undated, (8 folders) (Box 207)
        - Notes collected from others, 1992-1995, undated
        - Use of federal force, 1991-1995, undated
        - Weaver family, 1995, undated
      - Harris v. United States, 1994 (Box 208)
      - Justice Department
        - Correspondence and memoranda, 1993-1995
        - Press briefings and releases, 1994-1995
        - Reports
          - Miscellaneous, 1993
          - “The Shooting at Ruby Ridge,” excerpts from task force report, 1992-1995, undated, (2 folders)
      - United States v. Weaver
        - Exhibits, 1985-1995, undated, (2 folders)
        - General case material, 1992-1993, undated, (2 folders)
        - Index, 1993
        - Miscellany, 1991-1996
        - Trial transcripts (Box 209)
          - Individual testimony
            - Ayers, Stephen, 1994
            - Fackler, Martin, 1994
            - Fadeley, Kenneth, 1992
            - Horiuchi, Lon, 1992
            - Miscellaneous, undated
            - Rau, Ruth, 1993
          - Proceedings, 1993
            - June 2
            - June 3
            - June 9 (Box 210)
      - U. S. Senate Judiciary subcommittee hearings
        - Miscellany, 1993-1996, undated
        - Statements, 1995, undated, (3 folders)
        - Transcripts, 1995
          - July 27-Sept. 8, (5 folders)
          - Sept. 12-Oct. 13, (9 folders) (Box 211)
          - Oct. 18-Oct. 19, (2 folders) (Box 212)
      - Weaver v. United States
  - Shattuck, John, 1984, undated
  - Simon, Stanley, 1987
  - Spy cases
    - Conrad, Clyde Lee, spy ring
      - Articles, correspondence, interviews, and notes, 1990
      - Research material
        - Legal documents, 1990, undated
        - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1981-1990, undated
    - Cooke, Christopher
      - Articles and notes, 1981-1982, undated
      - Research material
        - Legal documents, 1981-1982, undated, (2 folders)
        - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1981-1982, undated
    - Kampiles, William (Box 213)
      - Articles, 1978
      - Interviews, 1978
      - Notes
        - Miscellaneous, 1978, undated
        - Trial, 1978, (2 folders)
      - Research material, 1978-1979
    - Miscellaneous articles and correspondence, 1978, 1987
  - Squid fisheries, 1986
  - Star Wars (Strategic Defense Initiative)
    - Articles, 1985
    - Interviews, 1985-1986, undated
    - Notes, 1982-1986, undated, (2 folders) (Box 214)
    - Research material
      - Congressional debate, 1975-1976, 1984-1986, undated, (2 folders)
      - Graham, Daniel O.
        - American Space Frontier Committee, 1982-1985, (3 folders)
        - High Frontier, 1976-1985, undated, (3 folders)
        - Miscellany, 1973-1976, undated
        - Westmoreland v. CBS Inc., 1973-1986, undated, (2 folders)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 215)
        - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1977-1985, undated, (3 folders)
        - Polls and press releases, 1983-1985, undated
  - Supersonic Transport (SST)
    - Articles, undated
    - Notes
      - Miscellaneous, undated
      - Notebooks, undated
    - Research material
      - Congressional debate, 1967-1971, undated
      - Boeing and General Electric documents, 1968-1970, (2 folders) (Box 216)
      - Legal documents and miscellany, 1966-1970, undated
      - Reports, 1965-1970, undated, (3 folders)
  - Teamsters
    - Central States Pension Fund
      - Articles, 1982-1983
      - Notes
        - Miscellaneous, 1982-1983, undated
        - Notebooks (Box 217)
          - Dorfman, Allen, undated
          - Guilty verdict, 1982
          - Lie detector tests, undated
          - Sentencing, 1983
          - Trial, 1982 (Box 218)
          - Weir, Ray, undated
      - Research material
        - Congressional hearing and reports, 1981-1983
        - Legal documents
          - Exhibits, undated, (2 folders)
          - General, 1977-1985, undated, (4 folders) (Box 219)
        - Miscellaneous, 1981-1985, undated
        - Newspaper clippings and related material
          - 1957-1966, 1977-1981, (2 folders)
          - 1982-1985, undated, (5 folders) (Box 220)
    - Guard bill, 1986
    - Hoffa, James R., 1971-1987, undated
    - Presser, Jackie (Box 221)
      - Articles, 1985-1986, undated
      - Notes
        - Miscellaneous, 1985–1986, undated, (2 folders)
        - Notebooks, 1985
      - Research material
        - Freedom of Information Act lawsuit, Lyndon H. LaRouche, 1985-1986
        - Legal documents
          - 1980-1986
          - Undated, (2 folders) (Box 222)
        - Miscellaneous, 1978-1986, undated
        - National Mediation Board, 1985-1987, undated
        - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1958-1961, 1970-1987, undated, (6 folders) (Box 223)
        - Reports, 1981-1986
        - U.S. Senate Permanent Subcommittee on Investigations, 1986
    - United States v. International Brotherhood of Teamsters
      - 1980-1989
      - 1990-1991, undated, (3 folders) (Box 224)
  - Telephone and communications excise tax, 1974, undated
  - Terrorism
    - Central Intelligence Agency reports, 1976-1981
    - Crane, Daniel, 1978-1981, undated
    - El Salvador, 1981
    - Federal Emergency Management Agency, 1970-1981, undated
    - General
      - Articles, 1973, 1981, undated
      - Correspondence, interviews, and notes, 1978-1981, undated
      - Research material (Box 225)
        - Miscellany, 1978-1986, undated
        - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1980-1986, 1995, undated, (3 folders)
    - Haig, Alexander, 1979-1981, undated
    - Heritage Foundation reports, 1980, undated
    - Institute for Policy Studies, 1980-1981, undated
    - Institute of Foreign Policy Analysis, 1983
    - Libya and Muammar Qaddafi, 1981, undated
    - National Committee Against Repressive Legislation, 1980-1981, undated
    - No More Witch Hunts Campaign, 1981, undated (Box 226)
    - PEN, Freedom to Write Committee, conference, 1981
    - Persian Gulf War, related attacks
      - Articles, 1991, undated
      - Research material, 1990-1991, (4 folders)
    - U.S. House of Representatives, Un-American Activities Committee, 1966-1968
    - U. S. Senate, Judiciary Subcommittee on Security and Terrorism
      - Articles, correspondence, and notes, 1981
      - Research material
        - Hearing records, 1981-1986, undated
        - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1971-1981, undated
    - Weathermen and FBI provocation, 1970-1981
  - Timber sales, 1975-1977, undated (Box 227)
  - Toobin, Jeffrey See also Containers 107-120, Iran-Contra Affair, and Containers 177-187, North, Oliver
    - Articles and correspondence, 1990-1991
    - Notes, 1990
    - Research material
      - General, 1985-1991
      - Legal documents, 1990-1991, (5 folders)
  - Unabomber manifesto, Theodore J. Kaczynski, 1995
  - United Service Organizations (USO), 1972, undated (Box 228)
  - United States Air Force, secrecy, 1953, 1982, undated, (2 folders)
  - United States Embassy, Moscow, Russia
    - Articles and correspondence, 1990
    - Interviews and notes, 1990, (3 folders)
    - Research material
      - Congressional debate and hearings
        - Correspondence and transcripts, 1988-1991
        - Reports, 1987-1990, (3 folders)
      - Miscellany, 1985-1990 (Box 229)
      - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1972-1991, (3 folders)
  - United States House of Representatives
    - Ethics Committee, 1955, 1965-1970, undated
    - Financial disclosure
      - Notes, undated
      - Research material
        - Disclosure forms, 1977 -1978
          - A-F, (3 folders)
          - G-Z, (6 folders) (Box 230)
        - Miscellany, 1976-1978
    - Select Committee on Assassinations See also Containers 130-144, Kennedy, John F., and Containers 146-148, King, Martin Luther, Jr. (Box 231)
      - Blakey, Robert, 1967, 1973-1979, undated
      - Budget
        - Articles, interviews, and notes, 1976-1977
        - Research material, 1976-1977
      - Closure of records
        - Articles, correspondence, interviews, and notes, 1981
        - Research material
          - Allen, Mark, file, 1980-1981, 1991
          - Miscellany, 1953, 1979-1981
      - Debate reviving inquiry
        - Article and notes, 1977
        - Research material, 1977
      - De Mohrenschildt, George, 1977, undated
      - Durham, William H., 1975-1978
      - Executive session, 1977, (2 folders) (Box 232)
      - Fauntroy, Walter E., 1973-1977, undated
      - Federal Bureau of Investigation
        - Newspaper clippings, 1977-1978
        - Released documents, 1964, 1974-1978, undated, (2 folders)
      - Final report
        - Articles, correspondence, interviews, and notes, 1979-1980, undated
        - Research material, 1977-1980, undated
      - Findings and recommendations, 1978
      - General
        - Articles
          - 1976
          - 1977-1981, undated, (2 folders) (Box 233)
        - Correspondence, 1976-1980, undated, (3 folders)
        - Interviews, 1976-1979, undated, (2 folders)
        - Notes, 1977, undated, (2 folders) (Box 234)
        - Research material
          - Committee hearings, 1977-1979, (2 folders)
          - Committee reports, 1976-1977
          - Miscellany, 1968-1969, 1975-1979, undated
          - Newspaper clippings and related material (Box 235)
            - Anderson, Jack, columns, 1977
            - Miscellaneous, 1967-1969, 1976-1979, undated, (7 folders)
          - Sprague, Richard E., 1967, 1977
      - Gonzales, Henry B., 1976-1977 (Box 236)
      - Hall, Loran, E., 1977
      - Hoch, Paul L., 1977-1983
      - Hosty, James P., and the FBI, 1964, 1975
      - Kennedy, John F., hearings
        - Acoustics
          - Articles, 1978-1981
          - Correspondence, interviews, and notes, 1978-1981
          - Research material, 1978-1981, (2 folders)
        - Acoustics and Dallas, Tex., police reports, 1976-1979, undated
        - Aleman, Jose, and Lewis J. McWillie, 1964, 1977-1978, undated
        - Autopsy, 1978 (Box 237)
        - Ballistic tests, 1977-1978
        - Castro, Fidel, 1975-1978
        - Conspiracy theories, 1978, (2 folders)
        - Cuba, 1978
        - Federal Bureau of Investigation, 1978 (Box 238)
        - Ford, Gerald R., and the FBI, 1965, 1977-1978
        - Helms, Richard, and Yuri Nosenko, 1976-1978
        - Opening day, 1963-1968, 1978
        - Oswald, Marina, 1978, (2 folders)
        - Photographs and Yuri Nosenko, 1978
        - Photographs and Yuri Nosenko, 1978 (Box 239)
        - Policy, 1978
        - Trafficante, Santo, Ralph Salero, and Burt Griffin, 1978, (2 folders)
      - King, Martin Luther, Jr., hearings
        - Articles, undated
        - Correspondence and interviews
          - Miscellaneous, 1976-1978, undated
          - Weisberg, Harold, 1977-1978, undated
        - Notes
          - Hearings, 1978, undated
          - Miscellaneous, 1976-1978, undated
        - Ray, James Earl, prison escape, 1977
        - Ray, John (Box 240)
          - Articles, correspondence, interviews, and notes, 1978-1979
          - Research material, 1974-1980, undated
        - Research material
          - Hearings, 1978-1979, (2 folders)
          - Law enforcement documents, 1964-1969, 1978
          - Mackenzie, Mary Lou, file on Ray guilty plea, 1968-1969, 1975, (2 folders)
          - Miscellany, 1968-1969, 1976-1978, undated, (2 folders)
          - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1967-1969, 1975-1978, undated, (2 folders) (Box 241)
      - Lane, Mark
        - Articles, 1977
        - Correspondence, interviews, and notes, 1976-1978, undated
        - Research material
          - Miscellany, 1963-1969, 1975-1978, undated
          - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1964-1978, undated, (2 folders)
      - Legal authority, 1977
      - Legislative history
        - Articles and notes, 1977, undated
        - Research material, 1976-1977, (2 folders) (Box 242)
      - McMillan, George, 1977
      - Meetings
        - Article and notes, 1976-1977, (2 folders)
        - Research material, 1976-1977
      - Members
        - Articles, interviews, and notes, 1976-1977, undated
        - Research material, 1974-1978, undated
      - Philadelphia, Pa., district attorney's office, 1974
      - Rules, 1977
      - Spending Committee (Box 243)
        - Notes, 1977-1978, undated
        - Research material
          - Miscellany, 1976-1978
          - Reports, 1976-1978, (2 folders)
      - Sprague, Richard A.
        - Firing and aftermath
          - Articles, 1977
          - Correspondence and interviews, 1977
          - Notes, 1977
          - Research material, 1977, undated
        - General (Box 244)
          - Interviews and notes, 1976-1978, undated
          - Research material, 1972-1977, undated, (2 folders)
      - Staff, 1975-1977, undated
      - U.S. Senate Select Committee to Study Government Operations, 1969-1976 undated
      - Weisberg, Harold, 1966, 1975-1978, undated
    - Un-American Activities Committee
      - Notes, 1959-1967, undated
      - Research material, 1961-1967
  - United States Senate, slush funds, 1981-1983
  - Veteran's Administration benefits, 1975-1976
  - Wallace, George C. (Box 245)
    - Governors Conference, 1974
    - Insurance premiums, kickback allegations
      - Article and notes, 1977
      - Research material, 1977
    - Miscellany
      - Articles and notes, 1966, 1984-1986
      - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1966-1969, 1977-1986, undated
    - Presidential election campaigns
      - 1968
        - Articles, 1968
        - Research material
          - Miscellany, 1968
          - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1968-1969
          - "Youth for Wallace" organization, 1968-1969
      - 1972
        - Articles, 1972, undated
        - Notes
          - Miscellaneous, 1972
        - Notebooks, 1972, (2 folders) (Box 246)
        - Research material
          - Campaign literature, 1972
          - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1972, undated
      - 1976
        - Article
        - Notes
  - Wallach, E. Robert
    - Articles, 1987-1989, undated
    - Correspondence, 1988
    - Research material
      - Articles by Wallach, 1990
      - Freedom of Information Act requests, Office of Independent Counsel
        - Lardner's letter of request, 1989
        - Meese, Edwin (Box 247)
          - Correspondence and memoranda, 1981-1987, undated, (2 folders)
          - Log of contacts between Meese and Wallach, 1981-1987
          - Schedules, 1981-1984
        - Wallach, E. Robert
          - Correspondence and memoranda, 1981-1985, undated, (3 folders)
          - Financial disclosure report, 1982
          - Photograph, undated
          - Response to independent counsel's report, 1988
      - Newspaper clippings, 1952, 1981-1990, undated, (2 folders)
    - United States v. Wallach (Box 248)
      - Legal documents
        - Exhibits A-E, 1987, (2 folders)
        - Grand jury indictment, 1987
        - Transcripts, 1989, (6 folders)
        - Wallach's memorandum on new trial, 1990 (Box 249)
      - Notes, 1988-1989, (5 folders)
      - Statement by Wallach, 1989
  - Watergate Affair
    - Articles, 1973-1974, undated
    - Break-in at Fielding office
      - United States v. Colson, 1973-1974, undated
      - United States v. Ehrlichman (74-116), (74-1882), and (74-1921), 1974, undated
      - United States v. Liddy (74-116) and (74-1885), 1974-1976
    - Break-in at Watergate complex (Box 250)
      - In re Grand Jury Proceedings, G. Gordon Liddy (73-1562), 1974
      - United States v. Hunt (73-2199), 1974
      - United States v. Liddy (72-1827), 1973-1974, undated
    - Campaign contributions
      - American Shipbuilding Co., 1973-1974, undated, (2 folders)
      - Articles, undated
      - Correspondence, 1973-1974, undated
      - International Telephone and Telegraph Co.
        - Articles, 1974, undated
        - Notes, 1974, undated
        - Research material
          - Legal documents, 1972-1974, undated, (2 folders)
          - Miscellaneous, 1972-1974
          - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1972-1974, undated
      - Notes, 1972-1973, undated (Box 251)
      - Research material
        - Legal documents, 1971-1975, undated
        - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1970-1974, undated
    - Chapin, Dwight, and Donald H. Segretti
      - Articles, 1974, undated
      - Correspondence, 1974, undated
      - Notes, 1973, undated
      - Research material
        - Legal documents, 1971-1975, undated, (2 folders)
        - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1973, undated
    - Cover-up
      - In re Application of U.S. Senate Select Committee on Presidential Campaign Activities (70-73), 1973, undated
      - Articles, 1974-1975, undated, (2 folders)
      - Correspondence, 1975, undated (Box 252)
      - Ehrlichman v. Sirica (74-1826), (74-1876), and (A-93), 1974, undated
      - Haldeman v. Sirica (74-1364), (74-1727), (74-1826), and (74-236), 1974, undated
      - Mitchell v. Sirica (74-1492), 1974
      - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1973-1975, undated
      - Notes, 1975
      - Strachan v. Sirica (74-1368) and (74-1868), 1974
      - United States v. Dean (73-886), 1973-1974
      - United States v. Haldeman (75-1381), 1975
      - United States v. LaRue, undated
      - United States v. Mitchell (74-110)
        - 1973
        - 1974
          - Mar.-Apr., (2 folders)
          - May-Oct., (6 folders) (Box 253)
          - Nov.-Dec., (2 folders) (Box 254)
        - 1975, (3 folders)
        - Undated
    - Cox, Archibald
      - Articles, undated
      - Correspondence, 1973, undated
      - Notes, 1975, undated
      - Research material (Box 255)
        - Legal documents, 1973, undated
        - Miscellaneous, 1973, undated
        - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1951-1977, undated, (4 folders)
    - Dean, John W., 1973-1974, undated
    - Defense attorneys
      - Articles and interviews, 1974-1977, undated
      - Notes, undated
      - Research material, 1962-1975, undated
    - Ehrlichman, John D.
      - Articles, undated
      - Research material (Box 256)
        - Legal documents, 1973-1974, undated
        - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1974
    - Enemies list, undated
    - Executive privilege
      - Articles, 1973, undated
      - Correspondence, 1973
      - Notes
        - Miscellaneous, 1973, undated
        - Notebook, 1972
      - Research material
        - Miscellaneous, 1959, 1972-1973, undated, (2 folders)
        - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1972-1973, undated
        - Statements and testimony, 1973, (2 folders) (Box 257)
    - Federal Bureau of Investigation, 1972-1973, undated
    - Haldeman, H. R., undated
    - Impeachment
      - Articles, undated
      - Correspondence, 1973
      - Notes, 1973-1974, undated, (2 folders)
      - Research material
        - Committee on the Judiciary
          - Report of proceedings, 1974
          - Selected material, 1973 (Box 258)
        - Law of impeachment, 1974
        - Miscellaneous, 1974, undated
        - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1973-1974, undated, (3 folders)
        - Summary of information, 1974
    - Jaworski, Leon, 1973-1977, undated (Box 259)
    - Kalmbach, Herbert W., 1973-1974, undated
    - Kleindienst, Richard G., 1973-1974
    - Krogh, Egil
      - Articles, 1973, undated
      - Notes, 1973, undated
      - Research material
        - Legal documents, 1973, undated, (2 folders)
        - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1973-1974, undated
    - McCord, James W., 1973-1978, undated
    - Milk fund investigation
      - Articles
        - 1971-1974
        - Undated (Box 260)
      - Correspondence, 1971-1975, undated, (4 folders)
      - Nader v. Butz
        - 1971-1973, (2 folders)
        - 1974-1975, undated, (3 folders) (Box 261)
      - Notes
        - 1971-1975
        - Undated
        - Undated (Box 262)
      - Research material
        - Legal documents, 1971-1974, (3 folders)
        - Miscellany, 1969-1979, undated, (5 folders)
        - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1963-1974, 1980, undated, (4 folders) (Box 263)
        - U.S. Senate Select Committee, 1972
        - Wright report, 1974 (Box 264)
      - United States v. Associated Milk Producers, Inc.
        - Legal documents, 1971-1974, undated, (3 folders)
        - Miscellany, 1971-1974, undated, (3 folders)
      - United States v. Connally, 1974-1975, (3 folders)
      - United States v. Jacobsen, 1970-1974, undated (Box 265)
    - Montoya, Joseph, 1970-1973
    - Notes
      - 1973-1976, (3 folders)
      - Undated
      - Undated, (4 folders) (Box 266)
    - Rebozo, Charles G. (“Bebe”), 1970-1975, undated
    - In re Report & Recommendations of June 5, 1972 Grand Jury... (74-21)
      - Articles, undated
      - Notes, 1973, undated (Box 267)
      - Research material, 1974, undated
    - Research material
      - Legal documents, 1974-1975
      - Miscellaneous, 1971-1974, 1983, undated
      - Newspaper clippings and related material
        - 1938-1966, 1972-1973, (3 folders)
        - 1974-1980, undated, (4 folders) (Box 268)
    - Richardson, Elliot L., 1973, undated, (2 folders)
    - Silbert, Earl J., 1973-1975, undated
    - Special Prosecution Force (Box 269)
      - Final report
        - Comments, 1975
        - Text, 1974
      - Status reports, 1974-1975
    - St. Clair, James, 1974, undated
    - Tapes
      - Articles, 1973, undated, (5 folders)
      - Correspondence, undated (Box 270)